[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；Kyle：从现场人群中的一些表情判断。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Judging from some of the looks on the faces in the crowd here in person.
这很有挑战性对吧？
This was challenging right?
我保证这会很有挑战性，我不想轻易放过你。
I promised that it would be challenging, I didn't want to let you off easy.
但实际上，当你意识到这是多么愚蠢的简单时，你可能会踢自己。
But actually you might kick yourself when you realize how stupidly simple this is.
它只需要你训练你的大脑
It just requires you to train your brain to
对这些问题有一些不同的看法。
think a little differently about these problems.
所以我要这么做
So here's what I'm gonna do.
我实际上要反向解决这个问题。
I'm actually gonna solve the problem in reverse.
因为我发现这样做更容易理解。
Cuz I find it easier to understand when I do that.
所以我要做的是假设我有一个getFile
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to assume that I have a getFile
实现这种魔力的函数。
function that does that magic.
会回来想办法让它变得神奇，但是
And will come back and figure out how to make it do that magic, but
我要谈谈我是如何使用这个函数的。
I'm gonna talk about how I use the function.
所以我需要从getFile中获取一些信息，并且
So I'm going to need to get something back from getFile, and
我拿回来的那件事就是一声巨响。
that thing that I get back is a thunk.
我会有三个，因为我要做三个单独的Ajax
And I'm gonna have three of them because I'm gonna make three separate AJAX
请求。
requests.
所以我把它叫做th1，thunk one，is getFile，file1。
So I'm gonna call it th1, thunk one, is getFile, file1.
Th2是getFile，
And th2 is getFile,
文件2。&gt；&gt；Kyle：和
file2. &gt;&gt; Kyle: And
Th3是getFile，file3，好吗？
th3 is getFile, file3, okay?
现在，这可以解决提出请求的问题，但是
Now, that takes care of making the request, but
它没有考虑到协调他们的反应。
it doesn't take care of coordinating their responses.
所以我要协调他们
So I'm going to coordinate their
回应。&gt；&gt；Kyle：使用
responses. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Using
就像我们知道Thunks的工作方式一样。
exactly the way we know how thunks work.
什么是thunk？
What is a thunk?
它需要一个回调，对吗？
It takes a callback, right?
所以我要调用th1，并给它一个回调，它给我一些文本。
So I'm gonna call th1 and give it a callback which gives me some text.
为了清楚起见，我将其命名为Text1。
And for just clarity's sake I'm gonna call it text1.
我们叫它什么并不重要。
It doesn't matter what we call it.
但我知道当存在Text1时将调用此回调
But I know that this callback will be called when there is a text1
回应。
to respond to.
大家都同意吗？
Does everybody agree with that?
所以我可以在这一点上简单地输出它。&gt；&gt；Kyle：和
So I can simply output it at that point. &gt;&gt; Kyle: And
然后我知道我可以调用Th2并传递一个回调。
then I know I can call th2 and pass in a callback.
&gt；&gt；kyle：在这一点上我知道我可以
&gt;&gt; Kyle: And at this point I know I can
打印出内容。&gt；&gt；Kyle：和
print out the contents. &gt;&gt; Kyle: And
然后我知道我可以用回调来调用它。
then I know I can call th3 with a callback.
&gt；&gt；kyle：并打印出内容，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: And print out the contents,
哎哟。&gt；&gt；Kyle：和
oops. &gt;&gt; Kyle: And
最后打印出我的完整信息。&GT；&GT；Kyle：好的，
finally print out my complete message. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Okay,
现在如果我的思维是懒惰的。
now if my thunk was lazy.
每个人都明白为什么我不并行发出Ajax请求了吗？
Does everybody see why I would not be making my AJAX request in parallel?
如果我的thunks是懒惰的，如果它直到那时才发出这个Ajax请求，
If my thunks were lazy, if it did not make this AJAX request until that point,
它直到Th1完成之后才会提出该请求。
it would not make that request until after th1 had finished.
这是一个有效的解决方案吗？
Is that a valid solution?
是的，除了它违反了我们平行要求的原则。
Yes, except for the fact that it violates our principle of parallel requests.
它可以工作，但不能满足问题的要求。
It would work, but it would not fulfill the requirements of the problem.
所以这个问题的要求是要求我们以某种方式拉一只兔子
So the requirements of the problem are going to ask us to somehow pull a rabbit
脱帽而出，创造出的不是懒惰的思维，而是积极的思维。
out of the hat and create not a lazy thunk, but an active thunk.
好吧。
Okay.
但如果我们真的有一个活跃的思维，大家能明白这是为什么吗？
But if we do have an active thunk, can everybody see why this is
总是要确保它们的响应顺序正确吗？
always going to make sure that they are responded to in the correct order?
这里有几个选择。
There's a couple of options here.
如果我运行th1并打印出其中一个的文本，然后我运行th2。
If I run th1 and I print out the text for one, and then I run th2.
一种选择是Th2已经准备好了，它已经有了响应。
One option is that th2 is already ready to go, it already has a response.
在这种情况下，它马上就会用text2打电话给我，
In which case it's right away gonna call me with text2,
这是一个选项，因为它已经有了那个选项。
that's one option, cuz it already had that one there.
另一种选择是还没有
Another option is that it's not yet
文本2准备好了，这种情况下我会继续等待。
got the text2 ready, which case I'm just gonna keep waiting.
但无论是哪种情况，我都知道一旦它着火了，我确实有一个text2。
But in either case I know that once it does fire I do have a text2.
一旦我到了3，只有两个选择之一。
And once I get to th3 there's only one of two options.
要么是Th3已经完成了，
Either th3 is already finished,
在这种情况下，当我调用它时，我会立即提取值。
in which case when I call it I'm gonna get the value extracted right away.
否则我不会马上提取价值，但是
Or I'm not gonna get the value extracted right away but
我会等到我有了一个值。
I'll wait until I do have a value.
所以在所有可能的组合中，这个表达式，
So in all possible combinations this expression,
这个嵌套的回调表达式将对我的输出进行排序。
this nested callback expression, is going to sequence my output.
我不需要担心任何类型的循环通过某个数组或
And I don't have to worry about any kind of looping through some array or
对象来查找东西。
object to find stuff.
我知道他们会被正确排序的结果。
I know that they're going to be sequenced correctly as a result.
每个人都听我的这个推理，好吗？
Does everybody follow me on that reasoning, okay?
无论你是否意识到，这是一个巨大的巨大进步，我们的
Whether you realize it or not, that's a huge massive improvement over our
之前，我们没有调用任何类型的库或任何奇特的东西。
previous, and we didn't invoke any kind of library or any fancy thing at all.
我们只是以不同的方式使用函数。
We're just using functions in a different way.
当我第一次意识到这一直都是可能的时，这让我大吃一惊。
This blew me away when I first realized that this was possible all along.
我到底为什么写了这么多年，
Why on Earth did I write so many years,
几十年的垃圾代码没有意识到如何更有效地使用我的工具？
decades of crappy code not realizing how to use my tools more effectively?
因为这明显更干净，更容易理解。
Cuz this is significantly more clean and understandable.
它并不完美，但它比我们在练习一中写的要好得多。
It's not perfect, but it's way better than what we wrote in exercise one.
现在我知道这就是我需要想出来的
Now that I know that that's what I need to come up with,
我需要弄清楚是否有可能解决。
I need to figure out whether it's even possible to solve.
这颗银弹，这颗活跃的子弹。
This silver bullet, this active thunk.
所以我们要这么做
So here's how we're gonna do that.
我们将观察到，每个thunk都有两种可能的情况。
We're going to observe that there are two possible cases for every thunk.
首先，我们知道自己是一个活跃的Thunk
First of all we know to be an active thunk
我们需要立即调用假Ajax调用。
we are going to need to call the fake AJAX call right away.
大家都同意吗？
Does everybody agree with that?
使用文件URL，以及
With the file URL, and
我们需要向它传递一些获得响应的回调。
we're going to need to pass it some callback that gets a response.
这必须发生在我们调用getFile的时候。
That's gonna have to happen right at the time we call getFile.
如果后来发生了这种情况，那么我们就会有一个懒惰的想法，我们的解决方案就失败了，好吧。
If that happens later then we have a lazy thunk and we've failed our solution, okay.
我们还知道thunk必须返回一个函数。
We also know that a thunk has to return a function.
并且该函数只需要接收一个参数，即
And that function needs to receive only one argument which is
回拨。&gt；&gt；Kyle：所以
a callback. &gt;&gt; Kyle: So
大家都明白这个道理吗？
everybody understand that reasoning?
因此，通过这种设置，我们需要获得第24行和第28行
So with this setup we have line 24 and line 28 need to get
以某种方式连接在一起。
bridged together in some way.
要么第24行运行在第28行之前，
Either line 24 is going to run before line 28,
或者第28行将在第24行之前运行。
or line 28 is going to run before line 24.
这是仅有的两种可能的结果。
Those are the only two possible outcomes.
所以我们需要在两者之间架起桥梁
So we need to bridge the two and
我们将通过独立地查看这两个场景来实现这一点。
we're gonna do that by looking at both scenarios independently.
因此，让我们想象一个例子，第24行首先运行，然后是第28行。
So let's imagine for an example that line 24 runs first, before line 28.
假设第24行已经运行，这意味着我们得到了响应。
So let's say line 24 has run, that means we got the response back.
但是我们还没有叫我们的thunk。
But we have not yet called our thunk.
我们需要保持这种反应，
We're gonna need to hold onto that response,
每个人都同意这个推理吗？
does everybody agree with that reasoning?
所以我要这么做
So here's what I'm gonna do.
在我的闭包中，我将有一个称为text的变量。
I'm going to, in my closure, have a variable called text.
我要说的是文本=响应。
And what I'm going to say is text = response.
现在第30行，这是之前的第28行。
Now on line 30 now, which was the previous line 28.
当第30行稍后运行时，我有一个回调和一些响应文本。
When line 30 runs at a later time, I have a callback and I have some response text.
所以我不能只说cb(文字)吗。
So couldn't I just say cb(text).
大家都看到我是怎么做到的了吗？
Does everybody see how I did that?
这只是我们两个场景中的一个，但是
That's only one of our two scenarios but
我只想让你明白我们是如何沟通的。
I just want you to understand how we're bridging.
在一个场景中，我们通过保存文本和
In the one scenario we're bridging by saving the text and
然后稍后将其传递到回调中。
then passing it into the callback at a later time.
好了，现在让我退后。
Okay, now let me back up.
现在让我们想象一下，在第26行之前，首先运行的是第30行。
Let's imagine that now instead that it's line 30 that runs first, before line 26.
所以第30行得到了一个回调，但是
So Line 30 gets a callback but
我们还没有准备好使用那个回调，是吗？
we're not ready to use that callback yet, are we?
所以如果我们把它保存下来，如果我们说fn=
So what if we save it off, what if we say fn =
CB。&gt；&gt；Kyle：和
cb. &gt;&gt; Kyle: And
然后，当这26行运行时，我有一个回调要传递我的东西，我可以
then when this line 26 runs I have a callback to pass my stuff to, I can just
只需将响应直接传递到fn。&gt；&gt；Kyle：Do
simply pass response directly into fn. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Does
大家都看到了吗？&gt；&gt；Kyle：所以在这两种情况中的任何一种
everybody see that? &gt;&gt; Kyle: So in either of
这两个场景我有办法弥合差距，而这个桥梁就是结束。
those two scenarios I have a way to bridge the gap and that bridge is closure.
现在我只需要把这两个解决方案放在一起，好吧。
Now I just need to put those two solutions together, okay.
所以我要做的，我会从头开始。
So what I'm going to do, I'll start back at scratch.
我要做的是设置一个if语句来请求这两个条件。
What I'm going to do is set up an if statement to ask for these two conditions.
所以在第26行，我要问的是fn是否已经设置。
So on line 26 what I'm going to ask is if fn has been set.
那我知道另一个先叫了，对吧，
Then I know that the other one has been called first, right,
因为这是唯一的方法。
cuz that's the only way it gets set.
这意味着我可以用我刚刚得到的东西直接调用它。
Which means I can simply call it right away with what I just got.
如果尚未设置fn，
If fn has not been set,
我需要保存响应。&gt；&gt；Kyle：在这里，
I need to save the response. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Down here,
我们要做相反的逻辑。
we're gonna do the reverse if logic.
如果文本已设置，则我知道我可以继续并将其发送给CB。
If the text has been set, then I know I can just go ahead and send it to cb.
否则，我需要保存我的回拨。
Otherwise, I need to save off my callback.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：你们中很少有人有这种感觉。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Few of you had that.
我让那个矿井像[声音]一样爆炸了。
I had that mine exploding like [SOUND].
怎么了？
What?
怎么会有这样的事而我根本不知道呢？
How has this been around and I just never even knew it?
在我多年的JavaScript生涯中，为什么从来没有人教过我这一点呢？
Why didn't anybody ever teach me this in all my years of JavaScript?
我不需要什么图书馆。
I don't need some library.
我只需要知道如何更好地使用我已经拥有的工具。
I just need to know how to better use the tools I already have.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：我看了，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: I've looked, and looked,
并为这两个国家的闭合的这种模式寻找了一个名字。
and looked for a name for this pattern of bridging the closure of these two states.
实际上，我问过函数式编程开发人员和
And really, I've asked functional programming developers and
其他人我怎么称呼这个模式？
other people what do I call this pattern?
没有人能给它起个好名字。
Nobody has any good name for it.
所以我把它叫做主动对被动，或者主动对懒惰。
So I just call it active versus passive, or active versus lazy thunks.
因为我没有更好的术语来形容它。
Cuz I don't have any better term for it.
但几年前当我发现这个的时候，
But when I discovered this a few years ago,
我开始到处使用它。
I started using it all over the place.
事实上，我意识到我之前已经摸索到了这个解决方案
And in fact, I realized I'd already kind of fumbled upon that solution before
在我早期的一些图书馆里。
in some of my earlier libraries.
因为在我有承诺之前我需要一些像承诺一样的东西。
Because I needed something like a promise before I had promises.
我在过去偶然发现了一些类似的东西。
And I had accidentally stumbled upon something kind of like this in the past.
然后我意识到，哇，这实际上是我在里面到处使用的模式
And then I realized, wow, that's actually a pattern I use all over place inside of
那里的各种图书馆，对。&gt；&gt；Kyle：所以
the various libraries there, right. &gt;&gt; Kyle: So
这是使用回调和
it's a more effective way of using the callbacks and
我们在语言中已经有的闭包。
closures that we already have in the language.
再一次，带走。
And again, the take away.
我们已经完全将时间作为方程之外的状态考虑在内。
We have completely factored time as a state out of the equation.
我们不用担心。
We don't have to worry about it.
我们设置这个代码一次，这就像管道。
We set this code up once, this is like plumbing.
这是我们反复编写的程序代码。
This is the program code that we write over, and over, and over, and over again.
这就是我们不必担心时间的地方。
And this is the part where we don't have to worry about time.
因为那部分已经为我们处理好了。
Cuz that part's already been taken care of for us.
因此，它使我们的代码从根本上更容易推理。
So it makes our code fundamentally easier to reason about.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：好的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Okay,
所以&gt；&gt；Kyle：那是雷声。
so &gt;&gt; Kyle: that's thunks.
下一步，当我们重归于好时，就是理解承诺是如何实现的
The next step, when we get back together, is to understand how promises
再加上这个模式，给我们提供更多的解决方案。
add on to that pattern and give us even more of a solution.
承诺不能代替雷霆。
Promises are not a replacement for thunks.
因为在我的图书馆里，我在制造雷声，我的意思是我在做出承诺，
Cuz inside of my libraries that I'm making thunks, I mean that I'm making promises,
我用雷鸣。
I use thunks.
雷鸣是你可以使用的东西，
Thunks are things that you can use,
这是解决异步排序问题的一种非常轻量级的方法。
it's a very lightweight way of solving asynchronous sequencing issues.
而不必调用一些巨大的库或一些疯狂的API或
Without having to invoke some huge library or some crazy API or
类似这样的东西，这是一种非常轻便，简单的方式。
something like that, it's a very lightweight, easy way of doing it.
需要一些练习才能让你的大脑绕过那个模式，
It's gonna take some practice to wrap your brain around that pattern,
我花了不少时间练习。
it took me quite a bit of practice.
会高度鼓励你从现在到下一次我们聚在一起
Would highly encourage you between now and the next time we get together for
这个车间，花点时间回顾一下。
this workshop, spend some time going back over that.
从空白文件尝试
Try that from blank file and
看看你能不能重现我刚才重现的那个推理。
see if you can recreate that same reasoning that I just recreated.
如果你这样做，我们对承诺的探索将会有更多的成果。
It'll make our exploration of promises a lot more fruitful for you if you do.